No one is safe
Safe House is a action, thriller film directed by Daniel Espinosa.
A dangerous CIA renegade resurfaces after a decade on the run.
When the safe house he's remanded to is attacked by
mercenaries, a rookie operative escapes with him.
Now, the unlikely allies must stay alive long
enough to uncover who wants them dead.
Tobin Frost, played by Denzel Washington.
Matt Weston, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Catherine Linklater, played by Vera Farmiga.
David Barlow, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Harlan Whitford, played by Sam Shepard.
Carlos Villar, played by Rubén Blades.
Safe House is a 2012 American action thriller film directed by Daniel Espinosa, written
by David Guggenheim, and starring Denzel Washington and Ryan Reynolds.
The film follows Matt Weston (Reynolds), a CIA officer on a low-level posting in Cape Town, South Africa, who is in charge of a safe
house where the CIA is interrogating Tobin Frost (Washington), a veteran operative accused of betraying the agency.
When the safe house is attacked by mercenaries,
Weston flees with Frost in his charge.
As the team of killers, who seem to be one step ahead of the pair, track
them throughout Cape Town, Weston wonders who to trust.
Vera Farmiga, Brendan Gleeson, Sam Shepard, Rubén Blades,
Nora Arnezeder and Robert Patrick co-star.
Safe House was Espinosa's first English-language film.
Filming took place on location in Cape Town.
The film premiered in New York City on February
7, 2012, and was released in U.S.
theaters on February 10, 2012, by Universal Pictures.
The film earned mixed reviews, with praise for Washington and Reynolds' performances, but
negative criticisms for the screenplay and the editing of the action scenes.
Nevertheless, the film was a commercial success, earning $208
million worldwide against an $85 million budget.
The film explores themes of martial arts, central intelligence
agency (cia), microchip, betrayal, on the run.
The tone is intense.